<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on Data viz, non-profits &amp; cats</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on Data viz, non-profits &amp; cats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Anastasia Kuprina 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Video Games</title>
      <link>/post/video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/video-games/</guid>
      <description>Using SteamSpy data, I was interested in seeing how many games are released on a daily basis. There was a clear trend in some days having higher number of new releases than others. It appears that most popular release day is Friday, followed by Thursday!
Total releases by dates The trend highlighted that there are a lot less releases on the weekends compared to the weekdays:
Original data: https://github.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/tree/master/data/2019/2019-07-30</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Women in the workforce</title>
      <link>/post/women-in-the-workforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/women-in-the-workforce/</guid>
      <description>TidyTuesday published data from the Census Bureau about women in the workforce. Equality and diversity are close to my heart and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass on this data. The data was showing - from all angles - that in categories that were given by Census Bureau, the pay gap is huge. At the same time, using same data, we can see what is the balance of females &amp;amp; males in the industry like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Remakes of Economist charts</title>
      <link>/post/economist-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/economist-charts/</guid>
      <description>tidytuesday-economist-remakes TidyTuesday had a task of redesigning the charts Economist mentioned at some point. Here is the original article: https://medium.economist.com/mistakes-weve-drawn-a-few-8cdd8a42d368
Original chart I chose to work with: Original chart (&amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo;) made in R: I did a small makeover to show the &amp;ldquo;remorse&amp;rdquo; part in more detail:
I like named y axis and I also prefer to have percentage sign there. As for &amp;ldquo;Wrong&amp;rdquo; being the highlight - the original chart is called Bremorse and (I guess) is meant to show the increase of people who believe their decision to vote &amp;ldquo;Leave&amp;rdquo; was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>